#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/samkirton (LinkedIn)

#### Top Skills

Solidity

Ethereum

**Smart Contracts** 

# Samuel Kirton

Tech Lead (Blockchain) at Noumena Digital AG

London Area, United Kingdom

#### Summary

Senior Software Engineer with 13 years experience developing mobile software solutions for; financial institutions, retailers, blockchain initiatives, and startups. I have been heavily involved in the design, architecture, and implementation of apps that have been successfully delivered to millions of users. https://github.com/memtrip

## Experience

NOUMENA DIGITAL AG

5 years 9 months

Tech Lead (Blockchain)

September 2021 - Present (3 years 10 months)

Zug, Switzerland

Senior Software Engineer (Blockchain)

October 2019 - September 2021 (2 years)

Zug, Switzerland

Multiple blockchain initiatives; full stack Typescript, proprietary DSL, message oriented architecture.

memtrip

Director

September 2013 - October 2019 (6 years 2 months)

London, United Kingdom

http://www.memtrip.com

Waracle

Senior Android Developer

June 2019 - September 2019 (4 months)

Edinburgh, United Kingdom

New features for apps related to pharmaceutical trials by Roche.

Infinity Works

Senior Android Developer January 2019 - June 2019 (6 months)

London, United Kingdom

New features/refactoring for the Sainsbury's Groceries app (1 million users).

NatWest Markets Plc Senior Android Developer May 2018 - November 2018 (7 months) London, United Kingdom

PSD2 dynamic linking requirements for FX app - Digital signatures, Onfido authentication, and exploring digital certificates for identity.

Waracle Senior Android Developer June 2017 - May 2018 (1 year) Glasgow, United Kingdom

Development of the Clydesdale bank app, with a focus on refactoring/code quality supported by increased espresso test coverage

Santander UK Senior Android Developer March 2016 - April 2017 (1 year 2 months) Milton Keynes, United Kingdom

Santander Retail Banking app (1 million users), developed from requirements to production in an XP team, guiding the implementation through strong unit and espresso test coverage.

Clydesdale Bank Senior Android Developer October 2015 - March 2016 (6 months) Glasgow, United Kingdom

Continued development of the B banking app

Deloitte Digital Senior Android Developer January 2015 - October 2015 (10 months) London, United Kingdom

Development of the B Banking App, from requirements to production (100k users).

Proffer Global Ltd

Android Developer May 2014 - January 2015 (9 months)

KPMG BlackBerry Developer August 2013 - March 2014 (8 months)

London, United Kingdom

Development of a reverse geocoding algorithm on memory restricted devices (J2ME). The app determines tax codes for U.S. based consultants who conduct business in multiple states per calendar month.

Monitise

BlackBerry Developer
June 2012 - June 2013 (1 year 1 month)

Mobile banking SDK and reference application. The Monitise solution powered the first wave of retail mobile banking applications in the UK. e.g; RBS, Co-op bank, Clydesdale Bank, and more.

Linksfield Technologies

.NET Developer

June 2010 - August 2011 (1 year 3 months)

Development and maintenance of a veterinary practice management software solution.

### Education

**Bournemouth University** 

Bachelor of Science (BSc), Software Engineering · (2008 - 2012)